<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on Sean Duffy</title>
    <link>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on Sean Duffy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Race Quad Build</title>
      <link>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2016/03/23/project-race-quad-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2016/03/23/project-race-quad-build/</guid>
      <description>For the past two years, the quadcopter I built has served me well. It&amp;rsquo;s had a lot of flight time, including had a few crashes and repairs, and still it flies very well. However, a couple of months ago I decided now was the time to venture outside of line-of-sight flying and into the world of FPV (First Person View).
Although it&amp;rsquo;s only been two years since I built my last quadcopter, a lot has changed in the multirotor hobby in that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Keyboard Conversion</title>
      <link>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2015/10/13/project-keyboard-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2015/10/13/project-keyboard-conversion/</guid>
      <description>Over the course of this year I have have developed an interest in mechanical keyboards, largely thanks to the /r/mechanicalkeyboards subreddit. This is probably one of the tech related niches that seems the strangest to outsiders, especially looking at the small subset of hardcore enthusiasts willing to pay hundreds of dollars for just a single keycap.
Nevertheless, outside of the obsession with novelty keycaps, having a keyboard that looks and feels good makes perfect sense for someone likely to be typing for a good many hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: ScraperWiki XLSX Endpoint</title>
      <link>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2014/09/08/project-scraperwiki-xlsx-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2014/09/08/project-scraperwiki-xlsx-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>This summer I was invited to work for ScraperWiki, and this post is about the project I spent most of my time on during this internship. The project in question was rewriting an endpoint that converts data in a SQL database to Excel Spreadsheet (XLSX) form for users to download and use. The current program was written in Python but was fairly slow and had the problem of consuming large amounts of system memory, sometimes causing failures in large datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Lights Out</title>
      <link>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2013/09/16/project-lights-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2013/09/16/project-lights-out/</guid>
      <description>This project is a Python recreation of the classic game Lights Out using the Tkinter package for the GUI, which I built a couple of weeks ago. It was very simple and didn&amp;rsquo;t take long, but I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be a good opportunity to use Tkinter and work on a fun puzzle game that I enjoy playing.
Lights Out was originally released by Tiger Toys in 1995 as an electronic puzzle game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Quadcopter Build</title>
      <link>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2013/09/10/project-quadcopter-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2013/09/10/project-quadcopter-build/</guid>
      <description>Quadcopters are something I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in for some time, when I first saw one I was amazed by the agility and stability it displayed and immediately wanted to know more. Being a programmer, the fact that carefully designed control software is the only thing that allows quadcopters to stay in the air furthered my interest. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve bought a couple of cheap RC quadcopters, which I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of fun flying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Portfolio Tool</title>
      <link>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2013/07/15/project-portfolio-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.seanduffy.co.uk/2013/07/15/project-portfolio-tool/</guid>
      <description>This is a web application I built in late 2012 while I was studying Computational Investing, an online course offered by coursera.org which provides an introduction to the programming side of quantitative analysis for finance, dealing particularly with hedge funds. I really enjoyed this course and I&amp;rsquo;d recommend it to anyone interested in computer science, finance, or both. It assumes only a basic knowledge of programming and pretty much no knowledge of finance or the stock market.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>